<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<units size='2'>
  <unit id='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature.feature.group' version='1.0.0.201401291103' singleton='false'>
    <update id='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature.feature.group' range='[0.0.0,1.0.0.201401291103)' severity='0'/>
    <properties size='8'>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='Arduino Designer'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='This modeler provides a way to program easily Arduino boards.'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://docs.obeonetwork.com/arduino'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='Obeo'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.type.group' value='true'/>
      <property name='maven-groupId' value='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino'/>
      <property name='maven-artifactId' value='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature'/>
      <property name='maven-version' value='1.0.0-SNAPSHOT'/>
    </properties>
    <provides size='1'>
      <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature.feature.group' version='1.0.0.201401291103'/>
    </provides>
    <requires size='9'>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='org.eclipse.gmf.runtime.notation.feature.group' range='0.0.0'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='org.eclipse.sirius.runtime.feature.group' range='0.0.0'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='org.eclipse.sirius.runtime.acceleo.feature.group' range='0.0.0'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='org.eclipse.sirius.runtime.ide.eef.feature.group' range='0.0.0'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='org.eclipse.sirius.runtime.ide.ui.feature.group' range='0.0.0'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='org.eclipse.sirius.runtime.ide.ui.acceleo.feature.group' range='0.0.0'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.design' range='[1.0.0.201401291103,1.0.0.201401291103]'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.branding' range='[1.0.0.201401291103,1.0.0.201401291103]'/>
      <required namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature.feature.jar' range='[1.0.0.201401291103,1.0.0.201401291103]'>
        <filter>
          (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
        </filter>
      </required>
    </requires>
    <touchpoint id='null' version='0.0.0'/>
    <licenses size='1'>
      <license uri='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html' url='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html'>
        Eclipse Public License - v 1.0&#xA;THE ACCOMPANYING PROGRAM IS PROVIDED UNDER THE TERMS OF THIS&#xA;ECLIPSE PUBLIC LICENSE (&quot;AGREEMENT&quot;). ANY USE, REPRODUCTION OR&#xA;DISTRIBUTION OF THE PROGRAM CONSTITUTES RECIPIENT&apos;S ACCEPTANCE&#xA;OF THIS AGREEMENT.&#xA;1. DEFINITIONS&#xA;&quot;Contribution&quot; means:&#xA;a) in the case of the initial Contributor, the initial code and&#xA;documentation distributed under this Agreement, and&#xA;b) in the case of each subsequent Contributor:&#xA;i) changes to the Program, and&#xA;ii) additions to the Program;&#xA;where such changes and/or additions to the Program originate&#xA;from and are distributed by that particular Contributor. A Contribution&#xA;&apos;originates&apos; from a Contributor if it was added to the Program&#xA;by such Contributor itself or anyone acting on such Contributor&apos;s&#xA;behalf. Contributions do not include additions to the Program&#xA;which: (i) are separate modules of software distributed in conjunction&#xA;with the Program under their own license agreement, and (ii)&#xA;are not derivative works of the Program.&#xA;&quot;Contributor&quot; means any person or entity that distributes the&#xA;Program.&#xA;&quot;Licensed Patents &quot; mean patent claims licensable by a Contributor&#xA;which are necessarily infringed by the use or sale of its Contribution&#xA;alone or when combined with the Program.&#xA;&quot;Program&quot; means the Contributions distributed in accordance with&#xA;this Agreement.&#xA;&quot;Recipient&quot; means anyone who receives the Program under this&#xA;Agreement, including all Contributors.&#xA;2. GRANT OF RIGHTS&#xA;a) Subject to the terms of this Agreement, each Contributor hereby&#xA;grants Recipient a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free copyright&#xA;license to reproduce, prepare derivative works of, publicly display,&#xA;publicly perform, distribute and sublicense the Contribution&#xA;of such Contributor, if any, and such derivative works, in source&#xA;code and object code form.&#xA;b) Subject to the terms of this Agreement, each Contributor hereby&#xA;grants Recipient a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free patent&#xA;license under Licensed Patents to make, use, sell, offer to sell,&#xA;import and otherwise transfer the Contribution of such Contributor,&#xA;if any, in source code and object code form. This patent license&#xA;shall apply to the combination of the Contribution and the Program&#xA;if, at the time the Contribution is added by the Contributor,&#xA;such addition of the Contribution causes such combination to&#xA;be covered by the Licensed Patents. The patent license shall&#xA;not apply to any other combinations which include the Contribution.&#xA;No hardware per se is licensed hereunder.&#xA;c) Recipient understands that although each Contributor grants&#xA;the licenses to its Contributions set forth herein, no assurances&#xA;are provided by any Contributor that the Program does not infringe&#xA;the patent or other intellectual property rights of any other&#xA;entity. Each Contributor disclaims any liability to Recipient&#xA;for claims brought by any other entity based on infringement&#xA;of intellectual property rights or otherwise. As a condition&#xA;to exercising the rights and licenses granted hereunder, each&#xA;Recipient hereby assumes sole responsibility to secure any other&#xA;intellectual property rights needed, if any. For example, if&#xA;a third party patent license is required to allow Recipient to&#xA;distribute the Program, it is Recipient&apos;s responsibility to acquire&#xA;that license before distributing the Program.&#xA;d) Each Contributor represents that to its knowledge it has sufficient&#xA;copyright rights in its Contribution, if any, to grant the copyright&#xA;license set forth in this Agreement.&#xA;3. REQUIREMENTS&#xA;A Contributor may choose to distribute the Program in object&#xA;code form under its own license agreement, provided that:&#xA;a) it complies with the terms and conditions of this Agreement;&#xA;and&#xA;b) its license agreement:&#xA;i) effectively disclaims on behalf of all Contributors all warranties&#xA;and conditions, express and implied, including warranties or&#xA;conditions of title and non-infringement, and implied warranties&#xA;or conditions of merchantability and fitness for a particular&#xA;purpose;&#xA;ii) effectively excludes on behalf of all Contributors all liability&#xA;for damages, including direct, indirect, special, incidental&#xA;and consequential damages, such as lost profits;&#xA;iii) states that any provisions which differ from this Agreement&#xA;are offered by that Contributor alone and not by any other party;&#xA;and&#xA;iv) states that source code for the Program is available from&#xA;such Contributor, and informs licensees how to obtain it in a&#xA;reasonable manner on or through a medium customarily used for&#xA;software exchange.&#xA;When the Program is made available in source code form:&#xA;a) it must be made available under this Agreement; and&#xA;b) a copy of this Agreement must be included with each copy of&#xA;the Program.&#xA;Contributors may not remove or alter any copyright notices contained&#xA;within the Program.&#xA;Each Contributor must identify itself as the originator of its&#xA;Contribution, if any, in a manner that reasonably allows subsequent&#xA;Recipients to identify the originator of the Contribution.&#xA;4. COMMERCIAL DISTRIBUTION&#xA;Commercial distributors of software may accept certain responsibilities&#xA;with respect to end users, business partners and the like. While&#xA;this license is intended to facilitate the commercial use of&#xA;the Program, the Contributor who includes the Program in a commercial&#xA;product offering should do so in a manner which does not create&#xA;potential liability for other Contributors. Therefore, if a Contributor&#xA;includes the Program in a commercial product offering, such Contributor&#xA;(&quot;Commercial Contributor&quot;) hereby agrees to defend and indemnify&#xA;every other Contributor (&quot;Indemnified Contributor&quot;) against any&#xA;losses, damages and costs (collectively &quot;Losses&quot;) arising from&#xA;claims, lawsuits and other legal actions brought by a third party&#xA;against the Indemnified Contributor to the extent caused by the&#xA;acts or omissions of such Commercial Contributor in connection&#xA;with its distribution of the Program in a commercial product&#xA;offering. The obligations in this section do not apply to any&#xA;claims or Losses relating to any actual or alleged intellectual&#xA;property infringement. In order to qualify, an Indemnified Contributor&#xA;must: a) promptly notify the Commercial Contributor in writing&#xA;of such claim, and b) allow the Commercial Contributor to control,&#xA;and cooperate with the Commercial Contributor in, the defense&#xA;and any related settlement negotiations. The Indemnified Contributor&#xA;may participate in any such claim at its own expense.&#xA;For example, a Contributor might include the Program in a commercial&#xA;product offering, Product X. That Contributor is then a Commercial&#xA;Contributor. If that Commercial Contributor then makes performance&#xA;claims, or offers warranties related to Product X, those performance&#xA;claims and warranties are such Commercial Contributor&apos;s responsibility&#xA;alone. Under this section, the Commercial Contributor would have&#xA;to defend claims against the other Contributors related to those&#xA;performance claims and warranties, and if a court requires any&#xA;other Contributor to pay any damages as a result, the Commercial&#xA;Contributor must pay those damages.&#xA;5. NO WARRANTY&#xA;EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY SET FORTH IN THIS AGREEMENT, THE PROGRAM&#xA;IS PROVIDED ON AN &quot;AS IS&quot; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS&#xA;OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION,&#xA;ANY WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY&#xA;OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. Each Recipient is solely&#xA;responsible for determining the appropriateness of using and&#xA;distributing the Program and assumes all risks associated with&#xA;its exercise of rights under this Agreement , including but not&#xA;limited to the risks and costs of program errors, compliance&#xA;with applicable laws, damage to or loss of data, programs or&#xA;equipment, and unavailability or interruption of operations.&#xA;6. DISCLAIMER OF LIABILITY&#xA;EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY SET FORTH IN THIS AGREEMENT, NEITHER RECIPIENT&#xA;NOR ANY CONTRIBUTORS SHALL HAVE ANY LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT,&#xA;INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES&#xA;(INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION LOST PROFITS), HOWEVER CAUSED AND&#xA;ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,&#xA;OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY&#xA;OUT OF THE USE OR DISTRIBUTION OF THE PROGRAM OR THE EXERCISE&#xA;OF ANY RIGHTS GRANTED HEREUNDER, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY&#xA;OF SUCH DAMAGES.&#xA;7. GENERAL&#xA;If any provision of this Agreement is invalid or unenforceable&#xA;under applicable law, it shall not affect the validity or enforceability&#xA;of the remainder of the terms of this Agreement, and without&#xA;further action by the parties hereto, such provision shall be&#xA;reformed to the minimum extent necessary to make such provision&#xA;valid and enforceable.&#xA;If Recipient institutes patent litigation against any entity&#xA;(including a cross-claim or counterclaim in a lawsuit) alleging&#xA;that the Program itself (excluding combinations of the Program&#xA;with other software or hardware) infringes such Recipient&apos;s patent(s),&#xA;then such Recipient&apos;s rights granted under Section 2(b) shall&#xA;terminate as of the date such litigation is filed.&#xA;All Recipient&apos;s rights under this Agreement shall terminate if&#xA;it fails to comply with any of the material terms or conditions&#xA;of this Agreement and does not cure such failure in a reasonable&#xA;period of time after becoming aware of such noncompliance. If&#xA;all Recipient&apos;s rights under this Agreement terminate, Recipient&#xA;agrees to cease use and distribution of the Program as soon as&#xA;reasonably practicable. However, Recipient&apos;s obligations under&#xA;this Agreement and any licenses granted by Recipient relating&#xA;to the Program shall continue and survive.&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute copies of this Agreement,&#xA;but in order to avoid inconsistency the Agreement is copyrighted&#xA;and may only be modified in the following manner. The Agreement&#xA;Steward reserves the right to publish new versions (including&#xA;revisions) of this Agreement from time to time. No one other&#xA;than the Agreement Steward has the right to modify this Agreement.&#xA;The Eclipse Foundation is the initial Agreement Steward. The&#xA;Eclipse Foundation may assign the responsibility to serve as&#xA;the Agreement Steward to a suitable separate entity. Each new&#xA;version of the Agreement will be given a distinguishing version&#xA;number. The Program (including Contributions) may always be distributed&#xA;subject to the version of the Agreement under which it was received.&#xA;In addition, after a new version of the Agreement is published,&#xA;Contributor may elect to distribute the Program (including its&#xA;Contributions) under the new version. Except as expressly stated&#xA;in Sections 2(a) and 2(b) above, Recipient receives no rights&#xA;or licenses to the intellectual property of any Contributor under&#xA;this Agreement, whether expressly, by implication, estoppel or&#xA;otherwise. All rights in the Program not expressly granted under&#xA;this Agreement are reserved.&#xA;This Agreement is governed by the laws of the State of New York&#xA;and the intellectual property laws of the United States of America.&#xA;No party to this Agreement will bring a legal action under this&#xA;Agreement more than one year after the cause of action arose.&#xA;Each party waives its rights to a jury trial in any resulting&#xA;litigation.
      </license>
    </licenses>
    <copyright uri='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html' url='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html'>
      Copyright (c) 2009, 2011 Obeo.&#xA;All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials&#xA;are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License&#xA;v1.0 which accompanies this distribution, and is available at&#xA;http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
    </copyright>
  </unit>
  <unit id='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature.feature.jar' version='1.0.0.201401291103'>
    <properties size='8'>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.name' value='Arduino Designer'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description' value='This modeler provides a way to program easily Arduino boards.'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.description.url' value='http://docs.obeonetwork.com/arduino'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.provider' value='Obeo'/>
      <property name='org.eclipse.update.feature.plugin' value='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.branding'/>
      <property name='maven-groupId' value='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino'/>
      <property name='maven-artifactId' value='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature'/>
      <property name='maven-version' value='1.0.0-SNAPSHOT'/>
    </properties>
    <provides size='3'>
      <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.iu' name='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature.feature.jar' version='1.0.0.201401291103'/>
      <provided namespace='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.eclipse.type' name='feature' version='1.0.0'/>
      <provided namespace='org.eclipse.update.feature' name='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature' version='1.0.0.201401291103'/>
    </provides>
    <filter>
      (org.eclipse.update.install.features=true)
    </filter>
    <artifacts size='1'>
      <artifact classifier='org.eclipse.update.feature' id='fr.obeo.dsl.arduino.runtime.feature' version='1.0.0.201401291103'/>
    </artifacts>
    <touchpoint id='org.eclipse.equinox.p2.osgi' version='1.0.0'/>
    <touchpointData size='1'>
      <instructions size='1'>
        <instruction key='zipped'>
          true
        </instruction>
      </instructions>
    </touchpointData>
    <licenses size='1'>
      <license uri='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html' url='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html'>
        Eclipse Public License - v 1.0&#xA;THE ACCOMPANYING PROGRAM IS PROVIDED UNDER THE TERMS OF THIS&#xA;ECLIPSE PUBLIC LICENSE (&quot;AGREEMENT&quot;). ANY USE, REPRODUCTION OR&#xA;DISTRIBUTION OF THE PROGRAM CONSTITUTES RECIPIENT&apos;S ACCEPTANCE&#xA;OF THIS AGREEMENT.&#xA;1. DEFINITIONS&#xA;&quot;Contribution&quot; means:&#xA;a) in the case of the initial Contributor, the initial code and&#xA;documentation distributed under this Agreement, and&#xA;b) in the case of each subsequent Contributor:&#xA;i) changes to the Program, and&#xA;ii) additions to the Program;&#xA;where such changes and/or additions to the Program originate&#xA;from and are distributed by that particular Contributor. A Contribution&#xA;&apos;originates&apos; from a Contributor if it was added to the Program&#xA;by such Contributor itself or anyone acting on such Contributor&apos;s&#xA;behalf. Contributions do not include additions to the Program&#xA;which: (i) are separate modules of software distributed in conjunction&#xA;with the Program under their own license agreement, and (ii)&#xA;are not derivative works of the Program.&#xA;&quot;Contributor&quot; means any person or entity that distributes the&#xA;Program.&#xA;&quot;Licensed Patents &quot; mean patent claims licensable by a Contributor&#xA;which are necessarily infringed by the use or sale of its Contribution&#xA;alone or when combined with the Program.&#xA;&quot;Program&quot; means the Contributions distributed in accordance with&#xA;this Agreement.&#xA;&quot;Recipient&quot; means anyone who receives the Program under this&#xA;Agreement, including all Contributors.&#xA;2. GRANT OF RIGHTS&#xA;a) Subject to the terms of this Agreement, each Contributor hereby&#xA;grants Recipient a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free copyright&#xA;license to reproduce, prepare derivative works of, publicly display,&#xA;publicly perform, distribute and sublicense the Contribution&#xA;of such Contributor, if any, and such derivative works, in source&#xA;code and object code form.&#xA;b) Subject to the terms of this Agreement, each Contributor hereby&#xA;grants Recipient a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free patent&#xA;license under Licensed Patents to make, use, sell, offer to sell,&#xA;import and otherwise transfer the Contribution of such Contributor,&#xA;if any, in source code and object code form. This patent license&#xA;shall apply to the combination of the Contribution and the Program&#xA;if, at the time the Contribution is added by the Contributor,&#xA;such addition of the Contribution causes such combination to&#xA;be covered by the Licensed Patents. The patent license shall&#xA;not apply to any other combinations which include the Contribution.&#xA;No hardware per se is licensed hereunder.&#xA;c) Recipient understands that although each Contributor grants&#xA;the licenses to its Contributions set forth herein, no assurances&#xA;are provided by any Contributor that the Program does not infringe&#xA;the patent or other intellectual property rights of any other&#xA;entity. Each Contributor disclaims any liability to Recipient&#xA;for claims brought by any other entity based on infringement&#xA;of intellectual property rights or otherwise. As a condition&#xA;to exercising the rights and licenses granted hereunder, each&#xA;Recipient hereby assumes sole responsibility to secure any other&#xA;intellectual property rights needed, if any. For example, if&#xA;a third party patent license is required to allow Recipient to&#xA;distribute the Program, it is Recipient&apos;s responsibility to acquire&#xA;that license before distributing the Program.&#xA;d) Each Contributor represents that to its knowledge it has sufficient&#xA;copyright rights in its Contribution, if any, to grant the copyright&#xA;license set forth in this Agreement.&#xA;3. REQUIREMENTS&#xA;A Contributor may choose to distribute the Program in object&#xA;code form under its own license agreement, provided that:&#xA;a) it complies with the terms and conditions of this Agreement;&#xA;and&#xA;b) its license agreement:&#xA;i) effectively disclaims on behalf of all Contributors all warranties&#xA;and conditions, express and implied, including warranties or&#xA;conditions of title and non-infringement, and implied warranties&#xA;or conditions of merchantability and fitness for a particular&#xA;purpose;&#xA;ii) effectively excludes on behalf of all Contributors all liability&#xA;for damages, including direct, indirect, special, incidental&#xA;and consequential damages, such as lost profits;&#xA;iii) states that any provisions which differ from this Agreement&#xA;are offered by that Contributor alone and not by any other party;&#xA;and&#xA;iv) states that source code for the Program is available from&#xA;such Contributor, and informs licensees how to obtain it in a&#xA;reasonable manner on or through a medium customarily used for&#xA;software exchange.&#xA;When the Program is made available in source code form:&#xA;a) it must be made available under this Agreement; and&#xA;b) a copy of this Agreement must be included with each copy of&#xA;the Program.&#xA;Contributors may not remove or alter any copyright notices contained&#xA;within the Program.&#xA;Each Contributor must identify itself as the originator of its&#xA;Contribution, if any, in a manner that reasonably allows subsequent&#xA;Recipients to identify the originator of the Contribution.&#xA;4. COMMERCIAL DISTRIBUTION&#xA;Commercial distributors of software may accept certain responsibilities&#xA;with respect to end users, business partners and the like. While&#xA;this license is intended to facilitate the commercial use of&#xA;the Program, the Contributor who includes the Program in a commercial&#xA;product offering should do so in a manner which does not create&#xA;potential liability for other Contributors. Therefore, if a Contributor&#xA;includes the Program in a commercial product offering, such Contributor&#xA;(&quot;Commercial Contributor&quot;) hereby agrees to defend and indemnify&#xA;every other Contributor (&quot;Indemnified Contributor&quot;) against any&#xA;losses, damages and costs (collectively &quot;Losses&quot;) arising from&#xA;claims, lawsuits and other legal actions brought by a third party&#xA;against the Indemnified Contributor to the extent caused by the&#xA;acts or omissions of such Commercial Contributor in connection&#xA;with its distribution of the Program in a commercial product&#xA;offering. The obligations in this section do not apply to any&#xA;claims or Losses relating to any actual or alleged intellectual&#xA;property infringement. In order to qualify, an Indemnified Contributor&#xA;must: a) promptly notify the Commercial Contributor in writing&#xA;of such claim, and b) allow the Commercial Contributor to control,&#xA;and cooperate with the Commercial Contributor in, the defense&#xA;and any related settlement negotiations. The Indemnified Contributor&#xA;may participate in any such claim at its own expense.&#xA;For example, a Contributor might include the Program in a commercial&#xA;product offering, Product X. That Contributor is then a Commercial&#xA;Contributor. If that Commercial Contributor then makes performance&#xA;claims, or offers warranties related to Product X, those performance&#xA;claims and warranties are such Commercial Contributor&apos;s responsibility&#xA;alone. Under this section, the Commercial Contributor would have&#xA;to defend claims against the other Contributors related to those&#xA;performance claims and warranties, and if a court requires any&#xA;other Contributor to pay any damages as a result, the Commercial&#xA;Contributor must pay those damages.&#xA;5. NO WARRANTY&#xA;EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY SET FORTH IN THIS AGREEMENT, THE PROGRAM&#xA;IS PROVIDED ON AN &quot;AS IS&quot; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS&#xA;OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION,&#xA;ANY WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY&#xA;OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. Each Recipient is solely&#xA;responsible for determining the appropriateness of using and&#xA;distributing the Program and assumes all risks associated with&#xA;its exercise of rights under this Agreement , including but not&#xA;limited to the risks and costs of program errors, compliance&#xA;with applicable laws, damage to or loss of data, programs or&#xA;equipment, and unavailability or interruption of operations.&#xA;6. DISCLAIMER OF LIABILITY&#xA;EXCEPT AS EXPRESSLY SET FORTH IN THIS AGREEMENT, NEITHER RECIPIENT&#xA;NOR ANY CONTRIBUTORS SHALL HAVE ANY LIABILITY FOR ANY DIRECT,&#xA;INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES&#xA;(INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION LOST PROFITS), HOWEVER CAUSED AND&#xA;ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,&#xA;OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY&#xA;OUT OF THE USE OR DISTRIBUTION OF THE PROGRAM OR THE EXERCISE&#xA;OF ANY RIGHTS GRANTED HEREUNDER, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY&#xA;OF SUCH DAMAGES.&#xA;7. GENERAL&#xA;If any provision of this Agreement is invalid or unenforceable&#xA;under applicable law, it shall not affect the validity or enforceability&#xA;of the remainder of the terms of this Agreement, and without&#xA;further action by the parties hereto, such provision shall be&#xA;reformed to the minimum extent necessary to make such provision&#xA;valid and enforceable.&#xA;If Recipient institutes patent litigation against any entity&#xA;(including a cross-claim or counterclaim in a lawsuit) alleging&#xA;that the Program itself (excluding combinations of the Program&#xA;with other software or hardware) infringes such Recipient&apos;s patent(s),&#xA;then such Recipient&apos;s rights granted under Section 2(b) shall&#xA;terminate as of the date such litigation is filed.&#xA;All Recipient&apos;s rights under this Agreement shall terminate if&#xA;it fails to comply with any of the material terms or conditions&#xA;of this Agreement and does not cure such failure in a reasonable&#xA;period of time after becoming aware of such noncompliance. If&#xA;all Recipient&apos;s rights under this Agreement terminate, Recipient&#xA;agrees to cease use and distribution of the Program as soon as&#xA;reasonably practicable. However, Recipient&apos;s obligations under&#xA;this Agreement and any licenses granted by Recipient relating&#xA;to the Program shall continue and survive.&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute copies of this Agreement,&#xA;but in order to avoid inconsistency the Agreement is copyrighted&#xA;and may only be modified in the following manner. The Agreement&#xA;Steward reserves the right to publish new versions (including&#xA;revisions) of this Agreement from time to time. No one other&#xA;than the Agreement Steward has the right to modify this Agreement.&#xA;The Eclipse Foundation is the initial Agreement Steward. The&#xA;Eclipse Foundation may assign the responsibility to serve as&#xA;the Agreement Steward to a suitable separate entity. Each new&#xA;version of the Agreement will be given a distinguishing version&#xA;number. The Program (including Contributions) may always be distributed&#xA;subject to the version of the Agreement under which it was received.&#xA;In addition, after a new version of the Agreement is published,&#xA;Contributor may elect to distribute the Program (including its&#xA;Contributions) under the new version. Except as expressly stated&#xA;in Sections 2(a) and 2(b) above, Recipient receives no rights&#xA;or licenses to the intellectual property of any Contributor under&#xA;this Agreement, whether expressly, by implication, estoppel or&#xA;otherwise. All rights in the Program not expressly granted under&#xA;this Agreement are reserved.&#xA;This Agreement is governed by the laws of the State of New York&#xA;and the intellectual property laws of the United States of America.&#xA;No party to this Agreement will bring a legal action under this&#xA;Agreement more than one year after the cause of action arose.&#xA;Each party waives its rights to a jury trial in any resulting&#xA;litigation.
      </license>
    </licenses>
    <copyright uri='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html' url='http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html'>
      Copyright (c) 2009, 2011 Obeo.&#xA;All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials&#xA;are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License&#xA;v1.0 which accompanies this distribution, and is available at&#xA;http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
    </copyright>
  </unit>
</units>
